我相信有天堂
I believe in heaven.
也相信有地狱
I also believe in hell.
虽未亲身体验  但我相信它们存在
I've never seen either, but I believe they exist.
不可以不存在
They have to exist...
若没有天堂
Because without a heaven...
没有地狱
Without a hell...
灵魂就失去了归宿
We're all just headed for limbo.
你不来吗
You coming?
要是情况不妙  护士会来找我们的
If it's bad, the nurses will come and get us.
格蕾医生  病人剧烈抽搐
Dr. Grey, he's seizing.
现在我们该去了吧
Well, how about now? Now can we go?
赛迪
Sadie...
去找点其他事情做
Go find something else to do, now.
这是命令
That's an order.
你怎么还在这儿
Why are you still here?
我是来陪你的  伊兹·斯蒂文斯
I'm here for you, Izzie Stevens.
不  你不是  我们已经分手了
No. no, you're not, because I broke up with you.
你不能来陪我
So you are not here for me.
我很抱歉  可是
I'm sorry, but...
你得离开了
You have to go.
我不能离开  我要陪着你
I can't go. I'm here for you.
陪着我  是的
Me, yeah, right.
我是真心来这里
I am. I'm here...
别说了
Stop saying that!
贝利医生
Dr. Bailey.
我刚打给器官捐献组织
I just called U.N.O.S.
杰克逊已正式获批  将优先接受
Jackson's officially at the top of the list
-肝脏与小肠移植  -我担心来不及
- For a liver and small bowel. - They can't come soon enough.
他的氨水平开始上升
His ammonia level's starting to rise.
我以为分流治疗能为他争取24小时
I thought the shunt was supposed to buy us 24 hours.
你不是说  这样可以多争取24小时吗
Isn't that what you said, that it should give us 24 hours?
穆兰达 我们已倾尽全力
Melinda, we're doing everything that we can.
我明白
I know.
我知道你们尽力了
I-I know you are.
失陪
Excuse me.
我的天哪
Oh, my god.
病人剧烈抽搐  已注射劳拉西泮[镇定剂]
He had a seizure. I gave him lorazepam.
你呼叫谢博德了
You page Shepherd?
我只呼叫了你
I paged you.
你该呼叫谢博德
Page Shepherd.
病人不愿意
The patient doesn't want that.
-是吗  他告诉你的  -没错
- Oh, really? He tell you that? - Yes.
别呼叫他  这人太惹人厌了
Don't page him. He's terribly unpleasant.
登先生与需要移植的孩子完全匹配
Mr. Dunn is a match for your kid who needs the transplant.
完全匹配
He's a match.
你可能造成了颅内出血
You probably have a brain bleed,
因此必须把谢博德找来
Which is why we need to get Shepherd in here.
贝利医生  他横竖都是一死
Dr. Bailey, he's gonna die anyway.
那个孩子需要器官才能活下来
The boy who needs organs, I presume wants to live.
而我
And me?
我有器官
I have organs.
我已生无可恋
And I'm ready to die.
斯隆医生
Dr. Sloan.
格蕾医生
Dr. Grey.
你先请  格蕾医生
After you, Dr. Grey.
谢谢  斯隆医生
Thank you, Dr. Sloan.
我知道这么做会内心不安
I know it feels wrong.
不管怎么想  都会内心不安
It feels wrong on so many levels, I can't even count them.
但任何医学资料上都未记载
But there is no case in any medical book
如何处理这种情况
That tells you how to deal with this situation.
不用看书都知道
Well, I don't need a book.
我知道该怎么做  为病人着想
I know what to do... what's best for my patient.
-我建议你也能如此行事  -我是为他着想
- I suggest you do the same. - I am.
你有吗  你呼叫谢博德了没
Oh, oh, really? You page Shepherd yet?
你打算呼叫他吗
Are you gonna page him?
我会尽我所能
I'm going to do my best
保住这个男孩的生命
To keep that beautiful boy alive
直到获得匹配的器官
Long enough to find him some organs.
我建议你也尽你所能
I suggest you do everything you can
保住你病人的生命
To keep your patient alive,
我们是医生  格蕾  不是刽子手
Because we're doctors, Grey. we're not executioners.
不会吧
Don't even tell me.
锁上了
Locked.
有人在睡觉  还是
People sleeping or...
我真是多此一问
Why do I bother asking?
太荒唐了  我要休息
This is ridiculous. I need sleep.
-这声音可不享受  -倒像是遭罪
- That's not a good noise. - That's a bad noise.
而且遭罪不浅
That's a really bad noise.
-天哪  你没事吧  -当然不
- Oh, my god. Are you okay?  - No.
从中间弯折了  我想是断了
It's bent in the middle. I-I-I think I broke it.
快去找托瑞斯
Get Torres!
快去
Go!
马上
Okay.
你们俩负责全天候看护杰克逊
You two are on Jackson all day today.
他没了肝和肠
He doesn't have a liver or intestines,
毒素会在体内积聚
Which means toxins are gonna build up
颅脑也会产生肿胀
And his brain is gonna swell.
我们无法阻止  只能尽力减缓症状
We can't stop it, but we can try like hell to slow it down.
-交给我了  贝利医生  -你无暇管这事儿  伊兹
- I'm on it, Dr. Bailey. - You don't have time for this, Izzie.
你无暇关心别人的事
You don't have time to think about anyone else.
斯蒂文斯  你最好点一下头
Stevens, I need a nod,
打个哈欠  或者打个嗝
a yawn or maybe even a little burp...
让我知道你是清醒的
Something that lets me know that you're awake
-有能力保护这孩子的生命  -是的  抱歉
And capable of keeping this boy alive.
是的  抱歉  一定全力以赴
Yes, I'm sorry. I am all yours.
-听你的没错  谢谢  -贝利医生
- Way to listen. Thanks for that. - Dr. Bailey.
还剩多少时间
How much tim do we have left?
最多16小时
16 hours at the most.
楼下有一台肝脏透析机
There's a liver dialysis machine downstairs.
肠胃科用来做临床试验的
G.I.'s using it for a clinical trial.
也许能为杰克逊再争取几小时  只是也许
It may give Jackson a few more hours. maybe.
那好  斯蒂文斯  接上颅内压监视仪
All right, then, uh, Stevens, put in the I.C.P. monitor
开始监控他的颅内压
And start tracking his intracranial pressures.
克莱夫  去把仪器拿来
Karev, go and get the machine.
万一仪器已经用在病人身上了怎么办
What if it's already hooked up to somebody?
如果那人所剩的时间超过16小时
If that somebody has more than 16 hours to live,
那就给他拔下来
Then we'll unhook 'em.
我想退出这个病例
I want off this case.
贝利医生
Dr. Bailey?
-老天  我想退出此病例  我要退出  -什么
- Oh, god. I want off this case. I want off of... - What?
这个小男孩活不了
This little boy is gonna die,
我不想眼看着他死去
And I just don't want to be there to see it.
我不想  我不能眼看着
I just don't want to... I can't see it.
我要退出  我要退出这个病例
I just want off. I want off. I want off this case.
我要退出
I want off.
你多久没睡觉了
When was the last time you slept?
不用  我没事
No, no, no. I'm okay.
我认为你该休息几小时
I think that you need to get one or two hours of rest.
我  我很好  我没事  你去忙吧
I'm...I'm good. I'm...I'm fine. Just go.
我没事  我很好
I'm good. I'm good. I'm good.
你很高兴嘛
You're very happy.
我很高兴  看见你真高兴
I am happy. I'm happy to see you.
-你却不高兴  -我在这守了一整晚
- You're not happy. - Oh, I've just been here all night.
那个变态病人怎样了
How is our resident psychopath?
死了没
Is he gone yet?
-是的  快了  -对了  妈妈喜欢你
- Uh, yeah, yeah, soon. - By the way, mom likes you.
她认为你很适合我
She thinks you're good for me.
托瑞斯医生  谢天谢地你在这儿
Oh! Dr. Torres, thank god you're here.
我得赶紧去急诊那
I'm headed down to the pit.
我收到紧急呼叫  有事找欧瑟尔去
I got a 911 page.Page Ortho if you need anything.
不  是我为斯隆紧急呼叫你的
No, no, it was me. i paged you 911 for Dr. Sloan.
他自己出了紧急状况  在他的私处
He's the emergency himself. It's on his person.
-等等  马克伤了  -是的
- Wait, Mark's hurt?  - Yes
-不可能  -真的  很严重
- No.  - Yes. he's badly injured
对每个男人都是致命打击的那种伤
In a bad way that is bad for anyone who's a man
对斯隆医生尤其严重
But for Dr. Sloan in particular.
他可能  可能断了根骨头
He may--he may have broken a-a bone.
-一根骨头  -是的  断了一根
- A bone?  - He broke a bone.
是我  我弄断的
I-I... I broke his bone.
你开玩笑呢吧
You're kidding, right?
克里斯蒂娜  我为昨晚的事向你道歉
Cristina, i wanted to apologize for last night.
昨天那样出现在你面前  不是我本意
It was not my intention to arrive in that state.
你不必解释的
You don't have to say anything.
按理来说
As a rule,
我要是与一个女人共浴的话
If i'm showering with a woman,
我起码得脱掉自己的衣服
I do it without my clothes,
而我要是光溜溜的进了她被窝
And if i get in her bed naked,
-我不会睡死过去的  要是...  -行了  没事
- I don't pass out, and if i...   - It's okay.
不行
It's not.
我是介意  但是
It's not... but, uh, you know,
你没必要解释
You don't have to talk about it.
呼吸起来越来越难了
It's getting a little harder to breathe.
你大可不必这么做的  威廉
You can stop doing this, William.
你随时可以停下来
You can stop at anytime.
我知道
I know.
我知道的
你要我去叫  谢博德医生吗
Do you want me to page Dr. Sheprd?
他是你男朋友  对吧
He's your boyfriend, isn't it?
猜中了
Yes.
我就知道
I had a feeling.
的确  我猜到了
Yes. I had a feeling.
这家伙品味不错啊
The man has very good taste.
此时此刻
Right now,
我能想到的全是柠檬
All I can think about are lemons.
柠檬
Lemons?
我祖父在濒临死亡的时候
When my grandfather was dying,
他说他闻到了柠檬的香味
He said he smelled lemons.
这让他足足回味了三年
It was all he could talk about for three days,
柠檬香味
The smell of lemons.
我老盼着闻这味道  可我闻不到
I keep waiting to smell them, and i don't.
当然啦  他是个大话王  所以
Of course...he was a big liar, so...
你确定不要我
Are you sure you don't want me
帮你去叫  谢博德医生
To page Dr.Shepherd?
确定
I'm sure.
好吧
Okay.
我要你去和护士们谈谈
I need you to talk to the nurses.
去找找有没有谁手上有病例
Find out if any of their patients on life support
是O+型血  或者是已经脑死亡的
Are o-positive or brain dead.
然后把那些人跟
And then crossmatch those folks
杰克逊 普里斯科特做交叉比对
Against Jackson Prescott.
-这孩子时间不多了  -好的
- The kid's running out of time.  - Okay.
还有  欧麦利
And, O'malley
要同情他们的家属
Be sensitive to their families.
我们是得给这孩子找器官  但我们只能询问
We need organs for this boy, but we can only ask.
我们不能游说  不能强迫他们  明白了没
We can't pressure.We can't coerce. Understood?
当然了
Of course, sir.
克里斯蒂娜
Cristina.
是个戒指
It's a ring.
这是我母亲的  是我的
It's from my mother. Oh, it's from me.
这曾经是我母亲的
It was my mother's
我打算过段时间  向梅瑞狄斯求婚
And i'm gonna give it to Meredith soon.
我需要你给我点建议
So what i'm looking for is an opinion
看看她会不会喜欢这戒指
On whether she's gonna like the ring,
还是我需要重新
Or I should have the setting redone
挑个更时尚些的
To something more modern.
这  这不关我事
Well, it's... That's really not my job.
听着  我知道你俩还在闹别扭
Right. Look, i know you two are still fighting.
但这不正是你俩和好的一个契机吗
But isn't it about time you wrap that up?
听着  我来问你是因为  我向她求婚的时候
Look, i ask because when i propose to her,
她需要一个人和她一起面对
She's gonna need somebody to freak out to.
她很想你
She misses you...a lot.
你一定也想她的  对吧
You must miss her, too, right?
我不知道你将来会发生什么
I don't know what's going on in your life,
但你一定也会遇到
But you must have something
需要她陪你一起面对的事情
You need to freak out to her about, too.
很抱歉  我觉得你问错人了
I'm sorry. I think you should ask someone else.
普里斯科特太太  您今天还没吃过东西吧
Ms.Prescott, have you had anything to eat today?
您可得保重身体啊
You should really keep your strength up.
去喝杯咖啡  吃点东西吧
Get a cup of coffee or some food.
我会在这儿陪着杰克逊的
I'll stay here with Jackson.
你就像那
You are like the guy
刚毕业的高中生
Who graduated from high school
老赖在足球场上
And still hangs out on the football field.
-你相信有天堂吗  -什么
- Do you believe in heaven?  - What?
天堂
Heaven.
我不知道
I don't know. I guess.
我曾以为  这儿就是天堂
Because I thought that maybe this was heaven,
在这儿  我能和你在一起
Getting to be here with you.
可如今  我犯浑了
But now... now I'm not so sure.
我觉得这儿
I think this...
我觉得这里或许是地狱或者
I think this may be hell or--
你瞎掰什么呢
What are you talking about?
-我是为你而来  -我是为你而来  我知道
- I'm here for you.  - I'm here for me, I know.
我明白  我都听了成千上万遍了
I got it. I hear you, a thousand times.
我选择阿历克斯了
I chose Alex.
对不起  我  对此  我真的很抱歉
I'm sorry. I am really sorry about that.
我不还在这儿吗
And i'm still here,
你和我分了手  我却还能在这儿
You broke up with me, and I'm still here.
难道你这还不能从中了解到什么吗
Doesn't that tell you anything?
我了解到你在嫉妒
It tells me that you're jealous,
你不想让我开心
That you don't want me to be happy.
你不想让我选阿历克斯
You don't want me to choose Alex.
靠  你听着  你不能选阿历克斯
Damn it, listen to me. You can't pick Alex.
-我是为你来这儿的  -丹尼
- I'm here for you.  - Denny...
我想让你开心  伊兹
I want you to be happy, Izzie.
我真的想的
I do.
该走的时候  我会走的
And i would leave if I could.
你告诉我  你要选别的男人
You think I want to stay here
你难道觉得  我还会想留在这儿吗
While you tell me you want another man?
我走不了  你压根就不听我的
I can't go because you won't listen to me.
我是为你来这儿的
I am here for you.
这到底是什么意思
What does that even mean?
是什么意思啊
What does it mean?
伊兹  你是个医生啊
You're a doctor, Izzie.
自己去想吧
Figure it out.
谢谢
Thank you.
干嘛
What?
是我刚才...怎么了
Did... What?
没什么
Nothing.
你那个连环杀人犯怎么样了
How's, uh, your serial killer?
你昨晚给他监听了吧
Did you monitor him last night?
当然
Yeah.
我都搞定了
I got it covered.
克里斯蒂娜  我说了我都搞定了
Cristina, I said I've got it covered.
-别告诉我你没叫谢博德  -他自己想死啊
- Tell me you paged Shepherd.  - He wants to die.
梅瑞狄斯  你怎么回事啊
Meredith, what are you--
几天后他迟早要死的啊
He's gonna die anyway in a few days,
他要死在这儿的话  我们能把他的器官遗赠
And if he dies here, we can donate his organs
给那个即将  在大厅里死去的10岁的孩子
To the 10 year old who's gonna die down the hall.
德里克不会同意的  所以我没呼叫他
And Derek won't allow it. So no, I didn't page him.
我希望你也不要
And I hope you won't either.
我知道你觉得这不对
I know you think this is wrong.
就随我的意思行不
Just let me do this.
求你们...
Please...
求你们救
Please help.
救我
Help me.
我  我还不想死
I... I don't want to die.
我不想死
I don't want to die.
立刻呼叫谢博德
Page Shepherd right now!
四楼出现紧急情况
Code blue, fourth floor.
我该插管了吗
Should I thread the catheter?
我想去看看大峡谷
I want to see the Grand Canyon.
确保能在超声波上观测到
Make sure you can visualize it on the ultrasound.
事实上  我想徒步旅行
I want to hike it, actually.
我想看人死去的人名坠落
I want to look out over dead man's drop
-用弯曲电导的方法  -不是因为我死了
- Use bend guidewire way.  - Not because I'm dead.
而是因为那景观
Just 'cause, you know, the view.
-闭嘴  -你说什么
- Shut up.  - What was that?
没什么  我该看着针尖吗
Nothing. Should I be able to see the needle tip?
是的  腔内的阴影就是导管
Yeah, that shadow within the lumen is the catheter.
有什么消息了吗
Have we heard anything?
器官捐献组织那有消息了吗
From U.N.O.S., have we heard anything?
我再打给他们
I'll call them back.
我还想去看看中国的长城
I'd also like to see the great wall of china.
你知道的  我这辈子去过很多地方
You know, I did a lot of traveling in my life,
但我从没去过亚洲  我挺后悔的
But i never made it to asia, and i regret that.
好了  斯蒂文斯 医生
Okay, Dr. Stevens,
我想说的是  你这个倔脾气女人
My point, you unbelievably stubborn woman...
除此之外  我还能看什么
Is there are other things I would like to do and see
不  这是利多卡因啊  你注意听了吗
No, that's lidocaine. Are you paying attention?
很多我想做的却做不了
Things that i would like to do, but I can't.
我既去不了天堂  地狱  也去不了亚洲
I can't go to heaven or hell or to Asia.
除了这我什么都做不了
I can't do anything but this...
直到你醒来  证实这一切
until you wake up and figure it out.
你不是已经告诉我了么
Wod you just tell me already?
对不起
I'm sorry.
-对不起  -你还是去休息下吧  史蒂芬医生
-I'm sorry.  -Why don't you take a little break, Dr. Stevens?
-听说斯隆的小弟弟被人弄断了 -真的么?
you hear sloan broke his goods?
就在寻呼室  上帝啊  我都能听到他叫了
in that on-call room. swear to god. i heard him screaming.
跟托瑞斯?
with torres?
可能   但不管是谁伤了他
maybe. but whoever it was,
那就是我想要的那种女人
that's a girl i want on me.
是托瑞斯干的?
was it torres?
我怎么知道  我是说  这不关我的事
how should i know? i mean, it's not my business.
这不关任何人的事  包括你在内
it's nobody's business, and it's definitely not yours.
我是说  我一点不知道
i mean, not--not--not that i know.
但如果我知道是谁伤了斯隆的小弟弟
but if i did know who broke mark sloan's penis
我也不会告诉你  因为我们连朋友都不是
i wouldn't even tell you because we're not even friends.
我拿出你的阑尾  这差点毁了我的前途
i mean, i took out your appendix and almost ended my career.
这没能让我们成为朋友
that doesn't make us close.
我希望他在20分钟内准备好进手术室
i want him prepped and into the o.r.in 20 minutes.
yes, sir.
好的
你早该呼叫我了
you should've paged me a long time ago.
当我问起他怎样时  你该告诉我真相
you should've told me the truth.
我只是想满足病人的愿望
better yet, whi was following how the patient's wishes.
他杀了5个女人
he killed five women.
就像你坚持自己的想法  我也坚持我的
as much as you believe you're right, i think i'm just as right.
如果我当时告诉你  那会引起一场争执
if i said something to you, there would've been a debate.
他从刚开始到这儿就操控了你
he's been manipulating you since he got here.
他专门捕食年轻女人
he preys on young women.
我以他医生的名义做了这个决定
i made a decision as his doctor.
这是个坏决定  是个错误的决定
it was a bad decision. it was the wrong decision.
你来参加他的手术
you're gonna scrub in on the surgery,
好好看着我如何不遗余力拯救他
and you're gonna watch while i try like hell
来弥补你错误的决定
to undo what you did.
他的颅内压快降到25以下了
his i.c.p.is not going under 25.
-导尿管阻塞了么 -没有
-Is the catheter occluded?  -It's fine.
好吧  试着调节下滴注器的高度
All right, try adjusting the height of the drip chamber,
-把床再调上10度  -这是做什么
-and let's raise his bed up another 10 degrees.  -What'll that do?
还不够
not much.
杰克逊  杰克逊  你听妈妈说
jackson. jackson, you listen to mommy.
现在还不是时候
it is not time.
你现在还不能放弃
you do not get to go yet.
你得在这里陪着我  听到么?
you have to stay here with me. you hear me?
你陪着妈妈  宝贝  现在还不是时候
you stay with mommy.it is not time, baby.
我爱你  我需要你去战斗
i love you, and i need you to fight.
我需要你去战斗  杰克逊
i need you to fight, jackson.
是  阴茎断裂
yeah, that's a penile fracture.
噢  我想自杀
oh, i'm gonna kill myself.
等我们动完手术你就能自杀了
we should operate, and then you can kill yourself.
-噢  天啊  -你能做手术?
oh, god. can you do it?
他?  噢  不  他是个非人类
him?  oh, no.he's a meatballer.
他做事细致  而且不会说出去
he is meticulous, and he will keep his mouth shut.
我以前做过类似的手术  不算太复杂
i've done operations like this before.it's not that complicated.
战场上常有这种事  是么
guys run into this problem on the battlefield, do they?
我不想跟你讨论士兵们
i don't think you and i should talk about
是怎么出现这种情况的
how guys run into this.
准备好手术室  我们得动作快点
uh, line up an o.r.we need to get in fast,
否则你就终身残废了
or you risk permanent damage.
噢  上帝啊  千万别让我终身残废
oh, god.no permanent damage, please.
嗨
hey
小格蕾  走开
little grey , go away
我不想让你见我这样
i don't want you to see me like this.
是我让你变成这样的
but i made you like this.
求你了
please
什么情况  欧麦利
talk to me, o'malley.
上帝
my god
这家伙不是器官捐赠者
the guy's not a donor,
他们试图把他拔出来
and they're about to unplug him.
谢博德医生
dr. shepherd.
贝利医生
dr. bailey.
我恳求你停下
i need...y-you to stop.
我恳求你放下手术刀
i need you to put down the scalpel.
这个男人企图自杀
this man is trying to kill himself,
求上帝宽恕  我希望你能满足他
and god forgive me, i need you to let him.
贝利医生  请你离开我的手术室
you need to leave my o.r., dr. bailey.
五天后  五天后这个男人就要死了
five days... in five days, this man is going to die,
他的器官将跟随他一同死去
and his organs are going to go with him.
他们会埋葬他的身体
they'll be buried with his body,
那些器官会在地下腐烂  这是种犯罪
and they'll rot in the ground, and that i-is a crime.
这是违背生命意志的犯罪
it's a crime against life.
而离这种犯罪只有五天了
it's only five days.that's it.
这就是为什么我们要从他身体里取出器官
that's all we're taking from him,
他根本不想要它们
and he doesn't want them anyway.
我们都曾经宣誓过  米兰达
we took an oath, miranda.
我知道
i know... that.
我知道我们宣誓过
i know we took an oath,
但现在  那些誓言已经没有意义
but... right now, that oath...makes no sense.
都毫无意义了  无意义
it makes no sense.it doesn't.
所以请你停下  停下
so just stop. just stop.
别再对这个人做任何挽救
don't do anything else for this man.
如果我停下这手术
if i stop this surgery...
那就和我把手术刀插进他的头颅没区别
it's the same as me sticking this scalpel into his brain.
这就是你想要的么?
is that what you want?
是的
yes.
这就是我想要的结果
that's what i want.
对不起  你想怎么做
i'm sorry.what do you want?
我知道这让你极度痛苦
i know this is excruciating.
但我想的是
but what i want...
我需要
what i need...
你丈夫的器官
are your husband's organs--
他的肝和肠
his liver and his bowels.
他是个匹配者
he's a match for--
走开
go away.
我很抱歉
i'm sorry.
请你走开
please go away.
我不能再承受更多了
i can't take anymore.
他本来是那么健康
he was healthy.
两天前他还是好好的
he was healthy two days ago.
我爱他
he's my love.
直到他把头往挡风玻璃上撞
and he put his head through a windshield,
而我必须把他拔出来
a-and i have to unplug him.
他本该是那个在困难时牵着我手的人
he is the person who is supposed to hold my hand when tngs go bad.
他应该是现在在这里求你们帮忙的人
he is supposed to be here to help.
但他将去向天堂
but he gets to go to heaven...
我再也承受不了什么了
and i can't take anymore.
我根本无法做到这些
i can barely do this.
所以  请你们离开
so please... go away.
我不想让任何人把他切开
i don't want anyone cutting into him.
你究竟去了哪里
where the hell have you been?
我
i, uh...
我有些麻烦事
i had some stuff.
与死去的人对话?
dead-man-talking stuff?
是的  我  我不知道
uh, yeah. i...i don't know.
这孩子将在他母亲面前死去
this kid is dying in front of his mom.
如果这还不算坏   贝利医生
it's so bad, dr. bailey--
贝利医生无法忍受站在这里看着他死去
dr. bailey--can't stay in here and watch.
这才是最坏的  但我们都在拼尽全力抢救
it's bad, but we're busting our asses to save him,
而你却在跟个死人说话
and you're talking to a dead guy.
如果你想在家里跟他说话  那没问题
look, you want to do that crap at home? fine.
但在这里不行  在这里  你是个医生
but not here.here, you're a doctor.
颅内压还是太高
i.c.p. is still way too high.
我刚给他注射了高渗盐水
i just gave him hypertonic saline.
他最后次吃劳拉西泮片是什么时候
when was his last lorazepam?
20分钟前我给他吃过一大片
i gave him a bolus 20 minutes ago.
给他点滴里注射肌肉松弛剂  继续监视
put him on a drip with vec and put him on a bis monitor.
用u.n.o.s继续检测
uh, check with u.n.o.s. again.
不管贝利在做什么
whatever bailey's doing,
我希望她比我们运气好点
i hope to hell she's having better luck than we are.
他在开颅时内出血
he's hemorrhaging through his craniectomy.
我是否该插入导管防止硬膜下出血
should i at least put in a subdural drain?
这由贝利医生决定
that's up to dr. bailey.
贝利医生?
dr. bailey?
贝利医生  我是否该插入导管
dr. bailey, should i put in a drain?
不
no
血流得太多  我们要尽快
there's a lot of bleeding.we should really do something soon.
我知道  杨医生
i am aware of that, dr. yang.
请快点决定
it's your call, dr. bailey.
贝利医生  这次你说了算
你来决定
it's up to you.
是刽子手
am i an executioner
还是医生
or am i a surgeon?
全在于你
it's up to you.
看你的了
it's your call.
动刀吧
pick up the scalpel.
他不能带走肝
he can't take his liver with him to heaven.
还有肠和肾
he can't take his bowels or his kidneys.
大脑已经坏死  但器官基本完好
his brain is gone, but those organs are probably good
他还年轻
because he's a young man.
我知道你不愿接受
and i know this is not what you want to think about,
这不是一般人能理解承受的
and it's more than anyone should ever have to think about.
但他确实不能带走任何器官
but he can't take his organs with him.
听说他以前是个理疗医师
I heard it was his physical therapist
在康复中心教瑜伽
from the rehaborl for who does this fancy yoga thing
身体蜷缩
where she, like, turns herself into a pretzel
倒立起来的时候是什么样的呢
she's on top of the guy
两周前她刚辞职
he quit two weaks ago.
大概是因为托瑞斯
I though it was Torres.
管她为谁呢  反正写入莱西·格蕾传奇了
Well, whoever ，it was going down Lexie Grey's history.
斯隆就是个神话
Sloan is a legend
想象得到那种肌肉吗
can you imagin the kind of muscle
黑人般强健的
it takes the black man like that, i mean
闭嘴 闭上你们的臭嘴
Shut up. just shut up about it.
你知道什么吧
you know something
我只知道这是别人的事
I know it is nobody's business
她肯定知道些情况
she totally know something
看见谁从房间里出来了么
did you see some body come out of the room
-说不定就是她  -什么
- may be it was her. - What?
是我  行了吧  是我
It was me, ok. it was me.
我在做瑜伽
i do this twist-and-shout thing
那能调节情绪的
that blows most guys' minds,
大概是练久了
and i guess i twisted I a little too far
汗水差点把衣服浸透
and almost took the whole thing off, okay?
我感觉得到你
i can feel you.
闻得到你
i can smell you.
你要是死了
if you're dead,
我怎么还能闻到你的味道
how i can smell your skin?
于是想着或许你还没死
so i'm thinking, maybe you're not dead.
可能
maybe that was
是我快疯了
the part of me that was crazy,
才会以为你死了
hat part that thought you died.
这一点也不夸张
maybe this is the not crazy part.
你还活着  不是吗  就是这样的
you are still alive, right? that's it.
对不起  不是这样的
i'm sorry, no.
是你的魂魄吗
are you a ghost...
还是我在做梦
or a dream or...
你是医生  伊兹  是个科学家
you're a doctor, izzie, a scientist.
相信科学
think like a scientist.
是  我是个科学家
i am! i am.
科学家相信眼见为实
scientists believe what they can see,
相信直觉
what they can feel...
事实  证据
facts--hard facts.
我能打你耳光  这就是事实
i slapped you. that is a fact.
手能碰到你的脸
i felt... your face on my hand.
这就是事实
fact.
感觉到你迎面而来的呼吸  这就是事实
I feel your breath against my skin. fact.
Fact. Fact.
伊兹
izzie.
伊兹  伊兹
izzie, izzie.
怎么了
what's happening?
告诉我
you tell me.
我害怕
i'm scared.
质谱仪波的幅度在加大
i.c.p. is still going up.
强力呼吸够么
are you hyperventilating him enough?
可以  pc02值是30
yes. his pc02 is 30.
不错  无论如何我们要让他醒过来
all right, let's raise him all the way up.
杰克逊  你要挺住
jackson, you have to hold on.
好吗  宝贝  挺住  一定要挺住
okay, baby? hold on. just hold on.
穆兰达  退后  你当着路了
Melinda, step back now. you're in the way.
再来包血清蛋白  你往后退
Hang another bag of f.f.p. you need to step back.
为妈妈挺住  好吗  求你了  jackson  求求你
hold on for mommy, okay? please, jackson. please.
普里斯科特女士
ms. prescott.
不 不 不
no. no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
你一定要救他  我不能离开他
you have to let them work on him. no, i can't leave my son.
-我不能  不能离开他  -我们出去等
- i can't. i can't leave him.  - we'll be right outside.
-求求你  让我留下  -我们出去等
- please. let me stay. please. please.  - we'll be right outside.
你处理废物吗
you seany bleeders?
这一块很干净
the field looks clear.
干得好  杨医生
nice work, dr. yang.
为什么停下来不继续呢
why don't you go ahead and close up?
谢谢
thank you, sir.
真可惜
what a waste.
他活过来了  格雷医生  我们救了条命
he's alive, dr. grey. we saved a life.
努力从来都不会白费
that's never a waste.
他还是个孩子
he's just a little boy.
从没有在外面过过夜
he's never had a sleepover.
还没骑过自行车
he's never learned to ride a bike.
穆兰达  穆兰达  听我说
melinda... melinda, listen to me.
会有奇迹的
miracles happen.
医院里每天都有奇迹发生
medical miracles happen every day.
还有人死而复生
people live. even when they shouldn't, they live.
我得陪着他
i need to be with him.
他从没离开过我
he's never been anywhere without me.
不能让他一个人走
he can't go alone.
我得陪着他
i need to be with him.
你一直都和他在一起
no. you are here with him.
即使不在手术室里
you're here for him even though you aren't in the room.
也在守护着他
you are. you are here for him.
是的
you're...
我就在你身边  伊泽 ·斯蒂文斯
i'm here for you, izzie stevens.
-就在你身边  -这不是真实的你
- i'm here for you. - you're not real.
我想告诉你  我就在你身边
i told you, i'm here for you.
不是真的  我感觉不到真实的你
you're not real. you are not real.
伊兹  我说过  会一直在身边守护你的
izzie, i told you, i'm here for you.
贝利医生请你进来
dr. bailey says you need to come now.
现在抱抱他吧
it's time to hold him.
他要走了  穆兰达  抱一抱让他安心走吧
he's going, melinda. hold him and help him go.
好的  宝贝
it's okay, baby.
走吧
you can go.
没关系
it's okay.
走吧
you can go.
没关系
it's okay.
妈妈没事的
mommy won't be mad.
走吧  杰克逊
you can go, jackson.
没关系
it's okay.
没关系的  杰克逊  走吧
it's okay, jackson. you can go.
有器官了
we have organs.
我们有器官了  第三手术室  现在
we have organs! get him to o.r. three now.
启动胸外按压
starting c.p.r.
回波平面成像35  来片碳酸氢钠
push .35 of epi. get me a bicarb.
腔静脉部分完成
finishing the vena cava.
放夹
releasing the clamps.
有黑点吗
okay, any black spots?
很干净
looks clean.
体温下降  启动心肺复苏
he's colding. start c.p.r.
推急救车
get the crash cart over here.
天堂还是地狱
heaven or hell?
对
yes.
你都在身边
you're here for me.
对
yes.
不对
no.
你不在身边
you're not here for me.
你在守护我
you're here for me.
你在守护着我
我想
i thought...
你就是我的天堂
you were my heaven.
我太爱你了
i loved you so much.
i loved you so much
当回到你身边
that when i got to come back for you,
我想
i thought...
你就是我的天堂
you were my heaven.
但可能
but maybe...
我是你的地狱
maybe i'm your hell.
我病了
i'm sick.
我病了  是吗
i'm sick, aren't i?
别说什么
and instead of telling me...
别说什么会救我
instead of telling me to save my life--
你这狗娘养的
you son of a bitch!
你这狗娘养的自私鬼  我恨你  我恨你
you selfish son of a bitch. i hate you! i hate you!
我不知道会有机会
i didn't know that there was a chance.
奇迹会发生  医学奇迹每天都发生
miracles happen. medical miracles happen every day.
你说的  你说过的
you said it! you said that!
滚开
leave!
滚
leave.
我现在可以走
i can go now...
因为你知道的
because you know.
但是这是你的选择
but it's your choice.
你要作出选择
you get to choose.
可是  伊兹  如果我走了
but   iz   if i go...
我不知道
i don't know...
我不知道能否回来
i don't know if i can come back.
如果我走了
if i go--
天堂地狱之间
in the choice between heaven and hell
我选择天堂
i choose heaven.
我选择生命  走开
i choose life. go.
离开这儿  走  离开这儿  滚开
get out of here! go! get out of here! go.
我真心希望这是天堂  滚啊
i really hope this is heaven. go.
你在等什么
what are you waiting for?
这个
this.
我活下来了
i'm alive.
是的  你活着
yes   you are.
我之前在玩弄你
i was playing you.
你男友说对了
your boyfriend was right.
我想摧毁你的事业
i wanted to destroy your career.
格蕾医生  我一直都在玩弄你
i was playing you the whole time   dr. grey.
我想活下来看看你受到的挫折
and i wanted to be here to see the fallout.
你害怕  威廉
you were scared   william.
死亡是吓人的
death is scary.
我也会怕啊
i would've been scared   too.
能在人群中展露友好的脸孔是好事
it'd be good to have a friendly face in the crowd...
当他们杀我的时候
when they kill me.
我整个晚上都计划好了
i planned a whole evening...
昨晚
last night.
一次真正的约会
a real date.
昨晚天空明朗
it was a clear night--
西雅图整一年也只有这么几次
one of the   uh   five seattle gets all year.
我本来打算带你去西点灯塔
i was gonna take you to the west point lighthouse
我们一起观看北边的灯光
and we were gonna watch the northern lights together.
我想要多一次机会
i'd like another chance.
我想你再给我一次机会
i want you to give me another chance.
你有问题
you got some problems.
你有严重的问题
you've got some big problems.
是
yeah.
是  是  我有问题
yeah   yeah   i do.
但你愿意与我约会吗
will you go out with me anyway?
愿意
yes.
请走开
please go away.
不
no.
小格蕾
little grey...
我不是小格蕾
it's not little grey.
我叫莱西
it's lexie.
还有就是  对不起
and... i'm sorry
我弄断了你的
that i-i broke y--
伤了你  我很抱歉
i'm sorry that i hurt you.
让你受辱了  我很抱歉
and i'm sorry that you're humiliated.
但我  我哪里都不去
but i'm--i'm not going anywhere.
我有个朋友  帮我看门
i-i've got a friend who is guarding the door--
一个好朋友
a good friend--
因为没有人会走进来
and since no one is going to be coming in
我  我打算爬进你的床
i'm--i'm--i am now going to climb into bed with you
抚摸你的头发
and i'm gonna stroke your hair
因为当我受伤时希望别人这么做
because that's what i like to have done for me when i'm hurt.
他现在如何
how is he?
我们这么迟才拿到那些器官
we were so late getting those organs in.
在脑水肿
between the cerebral edema
和缺血再灌注之间
and the reperfusion coding
我们不知道会对他的脑部
we--we don't know what kind of damage
造成何种伤害
was done to his brain.
我们不知道他能否醒来
we don't even know if he's gonna wake up.
我今天越线了
i crossed a line today.
我越线了
i crossed a line.
我也是
so did i.
天堂
heaven...
地狱  过渡地带
hell... limbo...
没有人真正知道我们何去何从
no one really knows where we're going...
柠檬
lemons.
原来我祖父没有说谎啊
my grandfather wasn't lying after all.
到达时又有什么在等待着我们
or what's waiting for us when we get there.
但是我们确信的一件事
but the one thing we can say for sure
胸有成竹的事
with absolute certainty...
杰克逊
jackson?
能让我喝点水吗
can i have some water?
是否某个时候会把我们带向另一地
is that there are moments that take us to another place...
我知道你不理解我
i know you don't understand me.
我自己也不能理解
i don't understand me.
我想向他表同情
i wanted to show him compassion.
这是我去看他的原因
that's why i went.
这就是原因
that's the reason.
但是很恐怖
and it was horrible.
很恐怖
it was horrible.
没事
it's okay.
她在车里
she's in the car.
她在车里不停地哭  你求婚了吗
she's in the car and she won't stop crying. did you propose?
没有  她去看威廉的死刑
no. she went to william's execution.
地球上的天堂时刻
moments of heaven on earth...
也许就是我们目前需要知道的一切
and maybe for now  that's all we need to know.